Harry Potter is a story about children in the 90s that never got to hear The Spice Girls.
There's also magic...
but that's a lot less interesting.
I'm not a Potterhead.
I'm a Potter SCHOLAR.
I know literally every sentence in Jake Rowling's books about Harry Potter and, er...
the other two...humans
I'll be using game footage, not to avoid copyright,
it's actually the second best way to experience the story after the Lego games.
Worst way is the books,
because you have to learn these...
"Symbols"...?
Okay then, let me tell you the entire story of Harry Potter.
Harry Potter and the Different Name Depending on Geographical Region
Sorcerer's Stone is correct.
It's not a philosophy stone, it's a STONE, used for SORCERY.
This is Harry.
His parents are dead.
And his adoptive parents are dicks.
Half-giant named Hagrid shows up and delivers the now famous line:
"You're a trust-fund kid, Harry."
So they go to the bank to look at his money.
They also grab a stone.
We find out Harry's parents were killed by Lord Voldemotch.
The wizard without a nose.
You aren't allowed to say his name, but it rolls SO well off the tongue!
I think that's even worse than killing parents.
Harry travels to the Wizarding School Hogwarts.
And we are introduced to the main characters:
Obviously, Harry Potter.
The boy who...
fell into luck potion as a baby, now he has the power of main character.
Ronald Weasley
Comedic relief, with a huge family, including Fred and George.
I like Fred!
Don't care for George.
The only thing I like about him is his left ear.
They also have their nerd, Hermione,
whose job it is to make Harry look better-
Essentially his manager.
Draco Malfoy,
a villain in four books and comedic relief in three.
And finally, Neville.
His talent is that he has no talents.
The main characters are sorted into Gryffindor House.
And now they have lessons with the Hogwarts teachers,
like McGonagall, a literal cat lady.
Professor Snape.
First described as:
... That can't possibly be foreshadowing.
Professor Obvious Villain,
and of course, most important of them all:
Madame Hooch!
Harry Potter is all about the Hooch.
Also Albus.
He's like a supervisor or something.
A troll shows up and is promptly killed by Ron.
Enjoy this while it lasts.
It's the one time you really shine throughout the series.
Harry gets an invisibility cloak.
And finds a mirror that ruins your day.
Then a centaur tells them to go check out the philosopher's stone,
but it's protected by tests.
First test: Giant Dog.
Can be beaten by music, or a hand grenade.
Second test: Evil Plants.
Defeated by a first-grader spell...
or a hand grenade.
Third test: a door.
Hand grenade, obviously
Fourth test: Chess.
Grenade! *explosion sound effect*
Fifth test: Poisons.
Haaaaahhh...
I give up.
No way!
The obvious villain was the villain! *shook*
But he's not alone, his turban holds...
... some random guy.
That's not Voldemort, he has a nose!
Then Harry murders him,
goes into a coma,
and wakes up to Dumbledore stealing his candy.
But Harry can only think about how good it felt.
Harry Potter and the Chamber of-
Declassified!
In the worst Harry Potter book everyone wants to kill HIM.
An elf tries to kill him,
a teacher tries to kill him,
His wife tries to kill him...
(and all those other filthy mudbloods!)
What is a Chamber of Secrets?
Well...
Hogwarts was founded in 990 AD.
It was not only the first Wizarding school,
it was also the first school with a...
Special needs class.
The founders were:
Two people no one cares about,
Salazar Slytherin,
and Chad Gryffindor.
Salazar knew, with the co-living,
guys would need a place to jack off.
So he built a chamber.
He was into all kinds of snakes,
even trouser snakes.
To not seem like a weirdo,
he made up a lie about killing normies.
Then a giant snake showed up.
The snake petrified a bunch of people,
so the gang decides Draco did that shit.
He didn't!
He just wanted to!
A ghost gives Harry a diary. The diary says:
Hi, I'm Tom Riddle.
Petrifying all those students?
Yeah, Hagrid did THAT shit.
Okay.
They caught him.
Mystery solved, game over!
The half-giant says one last thing:
"Follow the spiders".
What the fuck Hagrid.
Your last wish was to get Harry killed.
Oh noes!
Hermione has been petrified!
He's still not done!
Let's find the chamber.
Where is it?
Obviously in the Slytherin room.
Wait, it's on the toilet...!?
Was my jacking off theory correct?
Also, they kidnapped their professor and he erased his own memory.
*gasp*
Ginny Weasley did that shit!
And Tom Riddle is Lord Voldemort!
I can't BELIEVE Hagrid got Voldemort into his schemes!
Then a giant snake showed up.
How to deal with a snake encounter.
Never go into tall grass.
Don't bite your nails.
This kills the snake and ho-ly shit.
Is Harry Potter in Dude Perfect?
Riddle is dead and Ginny is like:
"Riddle made me do it! :("
Ginny...
"The voices told me to do it" is
not gonna hold up in court.
Yay!
Everything solved!...
Wait, what was up with the elf?
Malfoy did that.
Using an elf as a hitman is... probably illegal...?
Good thing money always wins in the magical world, too.
Teacher got his memory restored.
Then in 2017 people came forward with new allegations.
He is currently under police investigation.
I wonder how they deal with prisoners in the Wizarding World...
Harry Potter and the *movie sound* Bumpy Ride!
When it comes to prison, people talk about punishment versus rehabilitation.
In the Harry Potter world, they lock people up and torture them for the rest of their lives.
Really, really backwards place.
One of those people was Sirius Black.
... Then he left.
Ron's dad tells Harry:
"Hey lad, there's a murderous psychopath that wants to kill you."
[Harry]: "So do I need like, personal protection?"
[Arthur] "Harry! Don't be a pussy!"
The train gets searched by Dementors,
prison guards that don't get paid so they try to get a bribe out of the rich kid.
Too bad the new Defense teacher Lupin saves him
Oh, no!
Sirius Black is in the building!
And he destroyed a painting!
Harry is not worried about this murderous art critic.
But then he finds out he betrayed his parents!
... Doesn't like that.
Hagrid tries to kill Malfoy with a bird.
A dog drags Ron into a tree
the dog was Sirius, uh oh!
But Lupin is here. Ha they're buddies!
Sirius says, "Let's kill him!"
Bein--being oddly unspecific.
Hermono is like:
"I knew you were evil!"
You go out at night and howl!"
"You're a furry!"
"No, I'm a werewolf!"
"... And a furry."
They wanted to kill the rat!
... That turns out to be a rat looking guy.
How could he betray Harry's parents?
Oh-
WE know why.
[Peter] "I think my Animorph should be a Jaguar!"
[James] "You're becoming a rat and you're liking it."
Oh noes, the full moon is out, how incredibly unfortunate!
The rat escapes,
Lupin escapes, Sirius is dying,
and the cops show up to crash the party!
It's all over. Sirius Black is gonna die.
Then a glowing deer shows up.
They wake up in the hospital.
[Hermione] "Harry, I have a time travel device. Let's fix this."
[Harry] "Ah, yeah, mah mudblood."
"Wait, can't they fix everything with this?"
No, the Time Turner can't actually change the past...
For now.
So they go back and fix everything, the end.
Harry Potter and, er,
DidyouputyournameintheGobletofFire!?
The book starts with the Quidditch World Cup in England.
Magic hooligans must be fun.
Then Death Eaters -- mage Al-Qaeda -- attacks.
Brazil spent 800 million on security.
The Quidditch World Cup spent that times zero!
At the school Defence teacher Madeye Moody.
What a mean nickname.
This year, the school is hosting the Triwizard Tournament.
Competing against two segregated schools Beauxbatons and--
Durmstrang, that the Wiki says is in Sweden.
So honestly...
Go fuck yourself Hogwarts.
We're about to kick your Scottish arse.
Who's your most famous student?
A domestic terror survivor?
Compare that to a-
Global-
Quidditch-
Sensatiooooooon!
To enter the tournament, put your name in an inanimate object whose decision is above the government's.
Oh noes the dude on the cover got picked even though he's too young.
Albus asks him about it.
In the book calmly.
In the movie, he pushes him against the wall.
In the game, however, he doesn't say anything.
Dumbledore just stabs him.
First challenge: Steal an egg from a dragon.
Avada Kedavra!
That was easy. No property damage needed.
Next challenge: Breathe underwater.
Harry cheats and gets bonus points. That's BS. Where's the judge, the government representative?
Huh. He's dead. Obvious suicide, keep the tournament going.
Third challenge: A maze with a sphinx
And... Harry doesn't win. Edward wins,
but a Hufflepuff winner would be too weird
So they grab it together and end up in a graveyard.
A good character died. People can die in Harry Potter! Nobody's safe!
Seamus!
Then Voldemort gets resurrected.
Challenges Harry to a duel-
And loses.
Harry returns and causes a very awkward moment.
Brits and their cringe humor...
Eh, Moody was evil by the way.
But Voldemort is back, the scariest villain in the Harry Potter universe.
No, he's not!
Harry Potter and the- don't trust the government!
In long Harry Potter, Harry learns that Voldy isn't that bad compared to one mean teacher.
It starts with Harry chilling with his bro. Then Dementors do a drug bust
So Harry attacks an officer of the law and is expelled.
That was a short story.
Fucking trust fund kids and their lawyers.
At Hogwarts, Umbridge is the new defence against defence against dark arts teacher.
Doesn't teach them anything.
The government believes Voldemort is a false flag and doesn't want Dumbledore to create an army.
To disprove the claim about Dumbledore creating an army, the gang decides to create an army.
In the last book everyone dislikes Harry.
In this book everyone hates him.
So he should feel just at home.
Harry also has visions of his friends being tortured and is forced to take interrogation training with Snape.
Oh no, the guerrilla rebels got caught.
Huh? Everything went better than expected.
Then he sees Sirius has been taken.
His visions hasn't been correct so far, but Harry's betting it all on black.
Let's go to Umbridge office and teleport to him, and she catches them.
Umbridge decides to torture a 15 year old.
This is what happens when magical England is a one-party state.
Centaurs. Centaurs solve this.
The main characters fly dead horses to the Ministry of Magic to what could not possibly be a trap.
Oh, no it was trap!
Sirius Black gets killed and I should feel bad for Harry,
But it's established that love can stop an Avada Kedavra. So Harry just didn't love him enough.
Then we see Voldemort's second wizarding duel, and he loses again.
What if he's a really weak wizard?
But people just follow him because he's creepy
Harry Potter and the- Snape that killed Dumbledore
At Hogwarts, Snape becomes defense against art teacher.
Yes for the first time someone who is qualified.
The new potions teacher is Slughorn.
A person named Slughorn would change his name.
These books are getting unrealistic.
In one Potions class, Harry finds a book with all the answers written by the-
Half-Blood Prince.
Who is he? Who cares?
If I googled a school test and found all the answers,
I wouldn't assume it's a dark mystery, Hermonoi.
There's a rumor going around that Harry is the Chosen One.
He's not. I think Padma is the Chosen One.
I think she's got this Dark Lord situation.
Through the book, someone is trying to assassinate Dumbledore.
And he's terrible at it.
Harry thinks it's Draco again, but can't find any proof he's a Death Eater
So he decides to kill him. Worked before.
Now that Harry's a bad boy, Ginny kisses him.
And then a giant snake showed u-
Dumbledore wants a memory from Slughorn.
To get it Harry drinks luck potion making his luck--
No noticeable difference.
Now we can see Slughorn's memory.
Hey teacher if I was evil, I'm not obviously--
but if I was how would I get bonus lives?
Green mushrooms!
Or murder.
Voldemort put pieces of his soul into very obvious objects,
so he couldn't be killed.
Voldemort's uncle, Morfin-
Yes, his name was Morfin. It was a different time.
Had a ring and it destroyed Dumbledore's hand.
Horcrux Number Two is Slytherin's locket with a picture of a sombrero snake.
It's in a cave in a liquid of...
Based on Dumbledore's reaction-
I'm assuming root beer?
They get back and oh no! Draco is a Death Eater!
A useless Death Eater.
Then Snape shows up-
and Snape kil- no. No spoilers.
Harry Potter and the-
Road Trip!
Let's escort Harry to Ron's house.
The attempt causes Moody to die,
the bird to die and--
Naaaaaaaaaawwwwwww
Another Ron brother is getting married, and Lupin has a kid now.
Sucks the tension away from him
because now we know he can't die.
Then there's a government coup and the wedding is ruined.
The snake sombrero locket was fake and the real one is,
currently owned by Mega-Voldemort
So they break into the ministry.
What's up with the Wizarding World and security?
Turns out the locket was made in the land of Mordor.
In the fires of Mount Doom.
And can only be destroyed by very specific things.
Like the Chad sword.
It also gives Ron migraines so he leaves.
Another glowing deer tells Harry to jump in a lake.
But by happy chance, the Chad sword is also in the lake.
He dives in, and almost drowns.
Is saved by Ron, and then Ron accomplishes something for the third time this series.
They go to meet Alex Jones.
Get arrested, and taken to Draco's house and.
Finally, Hermione gets tortured.
It's usually the other two.
Harry contacts the hitman,
the hitman contacts the ratman.
The main man says to the ratman,
"Wanna join my team?"
And the rat guy strangles himself.
It's the best scene in the book and Warner Brothers didn't have the balls!
They leave and the elf dies.
From a knife! A muggle weapon
Impressive. Meanwhile Voldemort opens Dumbledore's grave.
And finds a note from Warner Brothers saying we like money.
Warner Brothers, and their what do you mean there's only seven books?
Horcrux Number Four is a cup hidden in a bank
Considering the Wizarding World security measures, they decide to rob the bank grab the cup and ride the dragon
Voldy, this is why people use offshore banks
Horcrux Number Five is probably Ravenclaw's diadem, they guess without any proof
They get into Hogwarts,
Snape is Headmaster
Snape is no longer Headmaster
Where's the diadem?
A ghost says the Horcrux is in a place Killian forgot to mention
So they go there and
uh oh time for the final duel
Minor character remembers he can't be the main character. So he sets the place on fire
Voldemort lays siege to a boarding school
Then there's an all-out battle with every character
Fifth Horcrux: Snake!
While searching for a magic mongoose
They find dying Snape and he gives them a memory
Back at Hogwarts
Lupin and wife dead
and, please tell me that you're-
NOOOOOOOOOOOOOO
Sony Memory Player
Snape and mummy were childhood friends
But Harry's dad bullied Snape and Lily found that irresistible
But Snape still loved her and to prove his love he took over Nakatomi Plaza
also joined Dumbledore
Voldemort makes reasonable demand
Potter agrees and gets killed
The second time a thing murders Harry Potter
The first thing was the Finnish book covers.
It didn't kill him
Is Voldemort in love with Harry? He meets Dumbledore in his head and Dumbledore tells him
Harry, I had a young boyfriend that runs a yoga studio in Glasgow.
How fast did he move on?
Is canon!
Joanne agrees with me!
Wait who's Joanne?
Harry wakes up and everyone starts to fight again
The Death Eaters are too powerful
It's all over everyone is going to die and Voldemort is gonna take over Magic Kingdom
Then the giant snake showed up
Neville! Neville was the chosen one.
The books makes this super obvious
The movies are way smarter about this. They only show us this by making him more handsome every year
Voldemort dies
Okay, who cares?
Who won the House Cup?
Slytherin, that's pretty biased
It's thirty (19) years later and Harry watches his kids get on the train
Harry Potter ends, and I completely forgot to talk about the Deathly Hallows
But that was the only thing I forgot throughout the entire series and that is the Kilian Experience
[Outro yo]